<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="story_content">
        <item>Once there were two rats who were good friends. One of them lived in a city and the other lived in a village. Both of them exchanged news of their well being through other The city rat and the village ratrats who travelled between the two places.
Once the city rat wished to meet his village friend. He sent the message through some rats of the village. The village friend was very excited about his friends visit. He made preparations to welcome him. To receive his friend, he went to the border of the village wearing a traditional dress like dhoti, kurta and cap, with a garland in his hand. However, his city friend was wearing a suit, boots and a neck tie. They hugged each other and exchanged greeting.
The village rat welcomed him and said, "We have fresh and unpolluted air here. The atmosphere in the city is impure."
They gossiped a lot and exchanged their views on different topics. Then, they sat down to eat. The village rat served him fruits and boiled wheat grains.
After having food, they went for a stroll outside the village. The fields looked green and the natural beauty of the jungle had its own attraction. The village rat said, "Does the city have such beautiful scenes?" The city rat said nothing but invited the village rat to come to the city at least once to see the comfortable life of the city.
The village rat said he would certainly come to the city one day. The city rat said, "Why don’t you accompany me now?" The village rat replied, "All right, I will consider your proposal.When the night fell, they came back and slept on the soft grass. Next day, for breakfast the village rat served his friend fresh fruits and cereals. The city rat was irritated and said to the village rat, "Let us go to the city right now. Give me a chance to serve you."
The village rat accepted the proposal and got ready for the journey to the city. The city rat lived in a big house. At night the village rat was surprised to see, the dining table full of different types of dishes. The village rat has not seen such a variety of food before. The city rat asked the village rat to enjoy the meal. Then he started eating. The village rat had a liking for the paneer and finished the piece quickly. At this moment, they heard the voice of a cat. The city rat said, "Quickly hide yourself below the almirah, otherwise the cat will eat us." Both rushed to the almirah and hid themselves under it. After some time, when the cat went away, both came out. The village rat was still trembling. The city rat again started eating the dishes and advised his friend too, "Do not be afraid. It is a part of the city life." The village rat gathered courage and went to the dining table again. This time he quickly finished the cake of his choice. At this juncture, a boy came there with a dog. The village rat being afraid of the dog asked his friend, "Who is this fellow?" The city rat said, "He is Jimmi, the son of the master of this house and the dog is his pet. Be quick and hide yourself there." After their departure, both the rats came out. The village rat was very afraid. He said, "Friend, I think I should go back now. I am thankful to you for the tasty dishes, but there are to many dangers. Thanks again." And he started for the village. On reaching, he heaved a sigh of relief and said, "Oh! Life is precious and above all wisdom."</item>
        <item> This ancient story from Greece describes King Midas as a greedy and discontented man, who loved gold more than anything else. Once, he did a good deed for someone, and a Greek God appeared before him, saying that he will be granted his heart’s desire for doing the good deed. Midas wished that everything he touched should turn into gold, instantly. The God granted his wish. Midas was very excited and went about touching random objects, turning everything he touched into gold. After a while, he became hungry. However, when he touched his food, it turned to gold, and he could not eat it. He was starving and dismayed that he could not eat. Seeing him troubled, his loving daughter threw her arms around him to comfort him, and she, too, turned to gold. Midas was horrified that his daughter had become a statue of gold. He regretted asking for the Golden Touch and realised that he had been greedy and that gold was not the most precious thing in the world. He cried and begged the God to take back his wish. The God took pity on him and asked him to take a dip in the river by his palace, and then fill a pitcher of water from the river and sprinkle it on all the things he wanted to change back. He followed the instructions and changed his daughter back to normal. He was very happy to get his beloved daughter back and stopped being greedy from that moment.</item>
        <item>This tale talks about the importance of hard work and planning for the future. The story tells of a grasshopper that spends the summer singing and idling away his time. Meanwhile, his neighbours, a colony of ants, work hard throughout the summer to store food for the winter. The grasshopper laughs at the ants and tells them that they should enjoy the summer. The ants tell the grasshopper that he should store food for the winter or he will starve when everything is frozen. When winter comes, the ants are in their nest, resting and surviving on the food that they stored. The grasshopper comes to their door, hungry and cold. He begs the ants for food and says he realised the error of his ways. The ants share their food with him and make him promise to work hard, next summer, to gather and store food.</item>
        <item>This is a story from The Arabian Nights: One Thousand and One Nights. It is a story full of magical adventures. It tells the tale of Aladdin, a poor tailor’s son. After his father dies, Aladdin’s mother earns money by spinning cotton. One day, a wicked magician comes to Aladdin and says he will pay him money for doing a small job. He also gifts him a ring as a token of advance. He then takes him to a hidden cave and asks him to go inside and bring him a lamp. The cave is full of gold and treasures. Aladdin finds the lamp and brings it to the opening of the cave. The magician asks Aladdin to give him the lamp, but Aladdin asks him to help him climb out of the cave, first. The magician gets angry and says magic words that trap Aladdin inside the cave. A desperate Aladdin absently rubs the ring on his finger, and a genie magically appears, saying it will grant him any wish. Aladdin asks the genie to help him get out. He then takes the lamp and goes home. He tells his mother everything. The next day, his mother rubs the lamp while cleaning it, and again, a genie appears. It grants Aladdin and his mother anything they wish for. They now become rich and live in comfort. Aladdin also marries the princess of the land and lives luxuriously in a palace built for them, by the genie. Meanwhile, the magician disguises himself as a lamp seller and comes to the palace, claiming to exchange new lamps for old. The princess gives away the magic lamp, not knowing what it really is. The magician then takes uses the genie of the lamp to take away Aladdin’s riches, palace and even the princess. Aladdin is in despair and tries to find a way to get everything back. He suddenly remembers the magic ring and uses the genie of the ring to bring back his palace, the lamp, and the princess. Aladdin then sets the genies of the lamp and ring free and lives happily ever after with the princess.
        </item>
        <item>The story goes that one Sunday morning, a red-faced caterpillar hatches from an egg on a leaf and begins to look for food. He eats a leaf, but is very hungry. He then eats through various foods, in increasing quantities, over the next five days. The caterpillar eats through one apple on Monday, two pears on Tuesday, three plums on Wednesday, four strawberries on Thursday, and five oranges on Friday. Then, on Saturday, the caterpillar has a huge feast of one piece each, of a chocolate cake, ice-cream cone, pickle, Swiss cheese, salami, lollipop, cherry pie, sausage, cupcake and watermelon. After this, the caterpillar gets a bad stomach ache from eating too much food. The caterpillar feels better on Sunday after he returns to his usual diet of a large green leaf. He then spins a cocoon around himself, in which he remains for two weeks. After two weeks, the caterpillar emerges from the cocoon, as a beautiful butterfly with colourful wings. This book teaches little children about numbers, names of various foods, days of the week, and the life cycle of a butterfly.
        </item>
        <item>This is a  funny bedtime story for kids. A proud and boastful emperor only cares about displaying himself in beautiful clothes and finery. He hires two weavers and promises them a reward if they make for him the best suit of clothes ever worn by anyone. The weavers are con-men who tell the king that they are using a special fabric that is invisible to anyone who is stupid or unfit for his position. The weavers are actually tricking the king, by only pretending to stitch the clothes, by miming making clothes. Thus, even though no one, including the emperor and his ministers, can actually see the clothes, nobody admits it, for fear of being called stupid or unfit for his position. The weavers claim to have finished the suit and mime dressing the emperor, who then marches before his subjects to show off his new clothes. The townspeople go along with this, as they do not want to admit that the king is naked and risk being called stupid. Then, a child who is watching the procession screams that the emperor has no clothes. The child does not understand the reason to keep up the pretence. Hearing the child, others in the crowd also join the child in saying that the emperor is naked. The emperor is very embarrassed. He realises that his pride and foolishness put him in a situation where he became the object of ridicule.
        </item>
        <item>Cinderella is another fairy tale full of magic and adventure. Once, a beautiful girl named Cinderella lived with her wicked stepmother and two stepsisters. The stepmother made her do all the housework and was very cruel to her. One day, the stepmother and stepsisters went to a ball in the King’s palace, leaving Cinderella behind. Cinderella really wanted to attend the ball and felt very sad that she had been left behind. Suddenly, a fairy godmother appeared in a burst of light, and she used her magic to transform Cinderella into a princess, wearing a lovely dress and glass slippers. She also turned a pumpkin and some mice into a carriage and horses, respectively. Cinderella could now attend the ball. The fairy godmother warned her that the magic will wear off at midnight and that Cinderella should return home before that. When Cinderella arrived at the ball, the prince saw her, and they fell in love. They danced together until midnight. When the clock struck twelve, Cinderella rushed to her carriage, leaving one of her glass slippers behind. The prince searched every house in town for the mysterious girl whose foot fit into the glass slipper. He reached the wicked stepmother’s house  and found that the shoe belonged to Cinderella. Thus, the prince and Cinderella got married and lived happily ever after.
        </item>
        <item>Once upon a time there lived a parrot in a forest. He was very handsome. His beak and wings were very beautiful. His younger brother also lived with him. Both were
living happily in the forest.A wise parrotOne day, a hunter came to the forest. He saw the pair of the parrots and thought, ‘These parrots are very beautiful and special. I will present them to the king,’ He spread his net in the jungle to catch them. Soon both the parrots were trapped.He kept them in a cage and went to the place. He said to the king, "O king, see this beautiful pair of parrots. I caught them in the deep forest. Seeing their beauty I decided to bring them to you. They will add to the beauty of your palace."The king was very happy. He gave one thousand coins to the hunter. He kept both the parrots in a golden cage and ordered his servants to look after them well.The parrots were looked after very well. They were treated as very important birds in the palace. They were served fruits and delicious food. They became the centre of attraction. Even the young prince came to play with them. The parrots were very happy. They got everything without any labour. The older parrot once said to his brother, "We are highly respected in the palace and hence, quite satisfied."
The younger brother replied, "You are right, we are getting royal treatment. It is our luck."One day, a hunter brought a black monkey named Kala Bahu. The monkey was presented to the king, who asked the attendants to keep the monkey in the courtyard. The king as well as the prince were very happy to see the monkey and his amusing activities. Soon the monkey became the centre of attraction.With the arrival of the monkey, the parrots were neglected. They sometimes did not even get food.Both of the parrots knew the cause of it. The older parrot was wise and hoped that the days would change again and one should not be depressed. He comforted his brother,"Nothing is permanent in this world. Have patience till the bad days are over."One day the monkey performed such feats before the prince that he got scared and cried, "Help! Help!" Hearing his cries, all rushed there and took the prince away.When the king came to know about it, he ordered his men to leave the monkey in the forest. The next day, the monkey was sent to the forest.The bad days of the parrots were now over. They were treated well again. Good dishes and fruits were also served to them. They again became the centre of attraction.The wise parrot clarified the situation to his younger brother saying that time never remains the same, and one should not be depressed by the temporary unfavorable changes. The young parrot also realized the fact that nothing is permanent in the world and one should never lose patience.
        </item>
        <item>The frogs in the lake had an easy life doing exactly what they wanted. But what pleased one frog annoyed another, and they could see things could be better. All thefrogs agreed they needed a strong leader to make the rules they should live by. So they sent a message to the King of all animals. "Very well," said the King, andthrew a log into a lake, telling the frogs this was their new leader.At first the frogs were terrified of it.When it splashed into the lake they all dived to the bottom and hid in mud. But after a while, when the log did nothing but float on the surface, they lost their fear.They hopped all over it and carried on as before.They sent another message to the King saying they needed a better one."Then you must learn your lesson," said the King. This time he sent a water snake,who took one look at all the frogs and ate as many of them as it could catch.
        </item>
            <item>There lived a hunter in a village with his family. He alos had a pet dog that was very faithful. One day , the hunter had to leave the house for one day, so
he went to the city with his wife. He left his son with his faithful dog. That night , a wolf came into the house and attacked the baby. On seeing this, the faithful
dog pounced over the wolf and fought with him. After a long fight the dog killed the wolf.The next morning, the hunter and his wife retruned from the city. The dog was
waiting outside for his master. When he saw his master, he licked its feet. The hunter saw the stains of blood on the dog’s mouth. He thought that the dog had killed
his son. He became very angry and killed the dog with his gun. Then he rushed inside to have a look at the baby. When he found his son safe inside him, he wept bitterly. MORAL:Haste makes waste.
     </item>
        <item>Four friendsThere were four friends named Mahesh, Ramesh, Rakesh and Mohan. They belonged to the same village. Once they were invited to attend a marriage function in a distant village. Therefore, they decided to go to attend the marriage party together.On the day of the marriage started their journey early in the morning, so that they could cross the forest before darkness falls.While they were crossing the forest cautiously, they could not enjoy its beauty because they were afraid of the wild animals. That’s why; they wanted to cross the forest speedily.By noon, they had crossed more than half the way. All of a sudden, Mahesh asked Ramesh, Rakesh and Mohan to stop and said, "There may be danger ahead as the area is known for its tigers. Let us check for the tigers first, then we will proceed further." They all looked here and there. At this moment, Mohan saw the tail of a tiger behind the bushes. He trembled with fear and cried, "There is a tiger behind the bushes! Now, what do we do? How can we save our lives?" Mahesh said, "Do not be afraid of the tiger. Have faith in God. We should pray to God. He will protect us."Ramesh climbed up a tree and said to his friends, "Do not waste time in talking. Quickly, climb up a tree. God helps those who help themselves. Be quick. Save yourself." So Mahesh, Rakesh and Mohan rushed to a nearby tree and climbed up. They all waited for the tiger to go. When the tiger went away, they descended from the tree. Thus, they crossed the forest safely and reached the village to attend the marriage party.
        </item>
       <item>Have you heard about the "Manobo tagselata k'alo"? These are men who live in that part of the world closest to the sun. As the sun rays are very hot at these parts, their skin is black because of the heat. To escape the scorching heat of the sun, they stay in a hole in the ground for the most part of the day.
           Do you know how they cook their food? Just before the sun rises, they put their rice into a big pot filled half with water and leave it without any fire beside their hole. Then they creep into their hole in the ground.
           When the sun rises, its hot rays cook the rice naturally. At noon, the black men come out of their hole and find their meal all ready for them. They quickly retreat into their hole with the big pot and have their meal.
           Then they work or play from noon till night. When night falls, they have leftovers from their afternoon meal and go to sleep.But they wake up early before the sun rises so that they can place their rice pot right on time. Then they again go down into the big hole
       </item>
        <item>The story starts on a farm, where a duck sits on a clutch of eggs to make them hatch. The eggs hatch one by one, and soon, there are six yellow-feathered ducklings, chirping excitedly. The last egg takes longer to hatch, and from it emerges a strange looking duckling with grey feathers. Everybody finds the grey duckling ugly, including its own mother. The dejected duckling runs away and lives alone in a swamp until winter comes. Seeing the duckling starving in winter, a farmer takes pity on the ugly duckling and gives it food and shelter at home. However, the duckling is afraid of the farmer’s noisy children and flees to a cave by a frozen lake. When spring comes, a flock of beautiful swans descend on the lake, and the duckling, which is now fully grown, but lonely, approaches the swans, fully expecting to be rejected. To his surprise, the swans welcome him. He looks at his reflection in the water and realises that he is not an ugly duckling anymore, but a beautiful swan. The swan joins this flock and flies off with his new family.
        </item>
        <item>This story is from Aesop’s Fables and impresses the importance of being truthful. It is the story of a shepherd boy who watched a flock of sheep near his
village. The area was known to have a wolf that was infamous for raiding the sheep flock and making away with a couple of sheep. Every villager knew of the menace and
was always ready to come to the aid of anyone who had a problem with the wolf. But the boy overlooked this helpful nature of the villagers, and in fact, ridiculed it.
For his amusement, he brought out the villagers, three times, by crying out for help, saying “Wolf! Wolf!”. The ever-vigilant villagers immediately came to help him,
only to find the shepherd boy having a hearty laugh. They were naturally upset when he laughed at them for getting fooled. One day, however, a wolf actually came and
started killing and eating his sheep. This time, when he cried for help, none of the villagers came to his aid, as they thought he was playing a prank on them again.
As a result, the wolf destroyed the shepherd’s flock. The moral of the story is that no one believes a liar, even when he tells the truth.
        </item>
        <item>One day,A boy was playing in a garden. He was running after butterflies and trying to catch them. He was very happy to see the colourful flowers.Then he
saw a frog skipping and jumping. As he ran behind the frog, it jumped into the pond.A cow was also grazing in the garden. He saw how the cow was chewing grass. A fly
then came there and buzzed over the cow. The cow swung her tail to make the fly move away. The child clapped and laughed.boy learn lesson from natureThe boy was
enjoying the beauty of nature. He said, "Nature is wonderful. Its beauty attracts everyone.When he saw a squirrel he ran after it and reached near the bed of roses. He
tried to pluck some of the roses, but a thorn pierced his finger. It was very painful.The boy started crying and ran to his house.His mother asked him, "What is the
matter? Why are you crying?" The boy said, "The thorn of the rose pierced my finger while I was plucking it and now I feel severe pain."His mother said, "It is your
mistake. You should not have tried to pluck the flower. The flowers are meant to be seen and not to be plucked. Besides, natural beauty should never be harmed. One
should notinterfere with the natural processes. Instead, we should help to maintain the nature."The son said, "I will always follow what you have just told, mama."The
Mother said,"Let me know what you have learnt today." Her son explained, "We should protect all living beings, whether animals or plants. We should never harm
them.Unnecessary interference with nature is harmful. It may harm the human beings in the long run."
        </item>
       </string-array>
</resources>